Hello! I'm Jimmy Wales, the Founder of Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia.
مرحبا! أنا جيمي ويلز مؤسس ويكيبيديا، الموسوعة الحرة.
Wikipedia depends on the generous donations of people from all over the world
تعتمد ويكيبيديا على تبرعات سخية من أشخاص حول العالم
People like you.
أشخاص مثلك.
The Wikipedia project started back in 2001, and has very quickly become
بدأ مشروع ويكيبيديا في عام 2001
one of the top-10 destinations on the Internet.
وسريعا أصبح من أعلى 10 مواقع على الإنترنت.
English is the largest language of Wikipedia, but
الإنجليزية هي أكبر لغة لويكيبيديا
what about the languages of the developing world?
ولكن ماذا عن لغات العالم النامي؟
We need to help foster the growth of Wikipedias in such languages as
نحتاج أن ننشط نمو الويكيبيديات في اللغات مثل
Hindi, Arabic, and Swahili,
الهندية والعربية والسواحيلية
languages where the speakers will really benefit from access to free knowledge.
اللغات حيث سيستفيد متحدثوها فعلا من الدخول للمعرفة الحرة
The following is some footage from the independent documentary film "Truth in Numbers"
التالي هو بعض اللقطات من الفيلم الوثائقي المستقل "الحقيقة في الأرقام"
When a child gets a laptop, there is a snap-shot of the Wikipedia
عندما يحصل طفل على حاسوب محمول، هناك مقالات من ويكيبيديا
both in their native language, and also some of the English Wikipedia as well.
بلغاتهم الأصلية والعديد من مقالات ويكيبيديا الإنجليزية أيضاً
That they can engage in
بحيث يدخلوا في نقاش مع بقية الناس حول أشياء موجودة في العالم
a critical discourse with other people about things that are out in the world,
ولا يأخذوا الأشياء كحقيقة مثبتة
that they don't have to take things at face value - that's a powerful idea.
هذه فكرة قوية
Part of the idea behind the the laptop is to expose kids to powerful ideas, and the
جزء من الفكرة وراء الحاسوب المحمول هي تعريض الأطفال لأفكار قوية
Wikipedia is one of those powerful ideas.
وويكيبيديا واحدة من هذه الأفكار القوية
Well, of course, my contribution is just a bit, but every little bit helps.
حسنا، بالطبع مساهمتي نقطة بسيطة، ولكن كل نقطة تساعد
So this is how I write in Wikipedia. Yes, it's a lot of work, but it works!
وهكذا أكتب في ويكيبيديا نعم، هو عمل كثير، ولكنه ناجح!
One day, we can put it on a disc and give it around the schools, so people can look it up.
في يوم ما سوف نضعها في قرص ونفرقها في المدارس حتى يستطيع الناس أن يبحثوا فيها.
All of a sudden, Wikipedia came and then this, the sum total of human knowledge - it struck me.
بشكل مفاجيء، أتت ويكيبيديا ثم - مجموع المعرفة البشرية.. لقد صدمتني.
You know the website Wikipedia? Yeah, yeah.
هل تعرف موقع ويكيبيديا؟ نعم، نعم.
So, I'm the Founder of Wikipedia. Okay, hi! Nice to meet you! It's a great site ...
إذا، أنا مؤسس ويكيبيديا حسنا، مرحبا! سعيد بلقائك! هو موقع رائع ...
Do you ever look at the ... ? ... and I also use pick-up lines from that.
هل تفتح ... ؟ وأستعمل أيضاً سطور لبدء التعارف منها.
Pick-up lines! From Wikipedia? Oh, yeah - did it work?
سطور بدء تعارف! من ويكيبيديا? آه، نعم هل نجحت?
One of the things that I've done is I've taken a copy of this whole website,
من الأشياء التي فعلتها هي إنني أخذت نسخة كاملة من الموقع، ويكيبيديا،
which is Wikipedia, and I've put it in a computer classroom where they don't have Internet access.
ووضعتها في فصل الحاسوب حيث لا يوجد إنترنت
If more of this was available in Afrikaans, it would be very useful.
إذا كان المزيد من هذا متوفرا باللغة الأفريكانية، سيكون مفيدا للغاية.
Actually, it's more important for developing countries than it is for developed countries,
في الحقيقة، ويكيبيديا مهمة أكثر للبلدان النامية أكثر من البلدان المتقدمة
because there is a gap, and this gap is purely knowledge
وذلك بسبب وجود فجوة، وهذه الفجوة عبارة عن المعرفة
it's not money, it's not politics or power or whatever, it's knowledge.
ليست نقوداً، ليست سياسة أو قوة أو أي شيء، هي معرفة
and we can look to a brighter future.
ويمكننا أن ننظر لمستقبل زاهر
Wikipedia has already changed the world, and with your continued support
لقد غيرت ويكيبيديا العالم بالفعل، وبدعمك المتواصل
there's no telling how much we can do for people internationally.
لا يمكن أن يقال ماذا نستطيع أن نفعل للناس حول العالم
Imagine a world in which every single person on the planet
تخيل عالماً بحيث يكون متاحا لكل شخص على وجه الأرض
is given free access to the sum of all human knowledge.
الدخول الحر والمجاني لمجموع المعرفة البشرية